What you are about to witness will contain
violence, disturbing imagery, adult themes,
and may leave you doubting who you thought you were.
Proceed at your own risk.
[♪ choir humming ♪]
[♪ soft piano ♪]
[♪ somber cello ♪]
[♪ choir building ♪]
[♪ chorus ♪]
[♪♪♪]
The day after the ground wept, the sun rose an hour earlier.
It set only 15 minutes early,
and no one noticed.
Well, someone noticed.
But it was a mere note scribbled down on parchment, lost and forgotten.
Until two weeks later, when the sun rose
an hour late and set two hours early.
Darkness was creeping in slowly, like hounds after a scent.
Ender man smelling blood in the air.
By late Reapmoon, there were only five and a
half hours of daylight, instead of the usual 11.
Even the thirstiest noticed the lack of light,
along with the lack of water.
Then came no sun at all.
The darkness was impenetrable, even for the sky.
Oh how they hoped and prayed.
The winter solstice would see dawn come again.
But still, she denied them.
The month of Dawnbloom came and went, and for the first time
in memory,
without Dawn ever blooming.
Hope began to decay, and desperation began forming like a
mould.
All of Vaildin would soon be rotting from within.
If not Dawnbloom, then perhaps during the Stormbloom.
"Perhaps the storms will bring us the sun?" they begged.
But the storms did not.
"Rasroth the Water Stealer"
"Rasroth the Salt Bringer"
"Rasroth the Sun Eater" is driven out of God's Din Keep.
But, out of respect for his brother the king, and the
sacrifice of his two wards as penance,
He is not killed then.
That night is the last night of Stormbloom.
Then, for the first time in four months, dawn splinters like
a revelation.
But she stays only an hour.
The entire month of green bloom, when spring should be
renewing Din,
the frosts melting and plants growing.
Trees budding.
The only thing growing, is unrest against the Crown.
The only thing budding, plots.
The fastest growing anything are the whispers.
(Help me when we cast him out.)
But it was only once the heir presumptive
was cast out that the sun returned.
(Perhaps more is needed?)
The only new growth this Greenbloom is treason.
(That's treason! No, it's a revolution...)
Revolution.
The day of the Rosebloom equinox,
the Sun rises at six, and sets at six.
After 12 hours of daylight, night falls, and...
so does the king.
The first rose bloom, of Rosebloom.
The King, of course, does not rise again.
Dawn, however, rises every single day after that,
as if breaking a fast.
Two weeks from now, after the sun has
set for the last time on the King,
the sun will not set at all.
Dalamure were domesticated long before Din.
[garbled chrrrp sound]
Although, the practice was lost for many years
before it was rediscovered by Highmarch merchants.
They are medium-sized mounts, ranging from
15 hands to 20 hands, depending;
originally bred for more vocational purpose.
Ostudans were bred for long-hauling cargo and wares.
Marsh Hoppers were used across the wetlands.
And in the mountains, we find the Boulder Ridge climbers.
[chirrp noise]
Their powerful legs and claws granting them their name.
Eventually, smaller, leaner breeds became
recreational racers.
Entertainment for all.
Every ward and their nobility is matched with a dalamure.
Most are bred specifically for the people of the crown,
and while the colours and patterns on the
coats and feathers change frequently and drastically,
the more refined breeders have perfected
the colours of the Wards.
They imprint on sight.
[chrrr noise]
Though it is not uncommon to see blinders
attached to the dalamure harness,
requiring the creature to rely on sound,
command, or magic to guide it.
The armour is intricate and fanciful,
with their human companions donning armour
and masks to match;
adorned with feathers, jewels, and sometimes
even dynlet stones.
Dalamures imprint for life.
This is not to say they cannot be useful, or
used, by anyone other than the one chosen,
but...
they will never bond, or be as devoted, as
they are to their companion of choice.
Once bound, a dalamure lives its entire life mute,
hanging on every word its companion utters.
Should their half fall before they do,
[chrrrping]
the dalamure begins to vocalise,
repeating sayings and phrases of their lost,
[garbled, corrupted] Slow up, now. Slow up.
[chrrping]
either out of grief, some say, or perhaps a strong recollection.
[garbled] Easy, now, boy.
This resonance is seen as abhorrent to many in Din
[chrrrrp]
and these faithful mounts are usually put down,
so that both companions can be truly laid to rest.
[distorted] Who's a pretty boy?
[chrrrp]
[distorted] I'll miss you.