What you are about to witness will contain
violence, disturbing imagery, adult themes,
and may leave you doubting who you thought you were.
Proceed at your own risk.
[♪ choir humming ♪]
[♪ soft piano ♪]
[♪ somber cello ♪]
[♪ choir building ♪]
[♪ chorus ♪]
[♪♪♪]
Life is... full of choices.
Decisions.
Forks in the road with
vastly differing destinations.
And we make our choices.
We pick the paths we set off on
for many, many different reasons.
We pick our paths.
All based on many,
many different things.
But each of those reasons can be
boiled down to the same few categories.
But each of those things can be boiled
down to the same few categories.
What we want.
What is wanted of us.
What we need.
And what is needed of us.
I made a choice, and now
I am facing the consequences.
And what is needed of us.
And I made my choice.
And after walking down the path that it
sets me on, I find myself at another fork.
And I'm paying for it.
And after walking down the path it set me on, I find myself at another fork.
I'm at a crossroads.
Be who they want me to
be, no matter the cost?
I am at a crossroads.
Be who they want me to
be, no matter the cost?
Or be who I was born to
Stand firm, or stand down.
I am at a crossroads.
I'm at a crossroads, and I have to choose a path.
And each path leads to a vastly differing destination.
Betray myself?
When I finally, finally look up
from the road that I walk on...
Or betray them?
Where will I find myself?